STAVROS TSOGKAS

MaRS Discovery District 101 College St., Toronto, Ontario, Canada http://www.cs.toronto.edu/~tsogkas email: tsogkas@cs.toronto.edu

Research Interests

My research interests are in the broad areas of computer vision and machine learning, currently focusing on image quality enhancement. I am also particularly interested in shape analysis, few-shot learning, and the use of mid-level representations to bridge the gap between bottom-up and top-down processing for problems such as object detection, segmentation and grouping.

Education

Université Paris-Saclay (CentraleSupélec)

Jan. 2016

Ph.D. in Mathematics and Computer Science

Thesis: Mid-level Representations for Modeling Objects

Advisor: Iasonas Kokkinos

National Technical University of Athens

Sep. 2011

Diploma in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Thesis: Learning-Based Symmetry Detection in Natural Images

Advisors: Petros Maragos, Iasonas Kokkinos

Research Experience

Samsung AI Center Toronto

Sep. 2018 - present

Research Scientist

University of Toronto

Oct. 2019 - Jul. 2021

Adjunct Professor

Vector Institute for Artificial Intelligence

Jan. 2018 - Jan. 2019

Affiliate postdoctoral fellow

University of Toronto

Oct. 2016 - Oct. 2019

Postdoctoral fellow, Computer Science Department

Supervisor: Sven Dickinson

CentraleSupélec

Jan. 2016 - Aug. 2016

Research engineer, CVN lab Supervisor: Nikos Paragios

Convolutional neural networks for semantic segmentation of organs in computed tomography scans.

Oxford University (Visual Geometry Group)

Aug.-Nov. 2014

Research intern

Supervisor: Andrea Vedaldi.

Combined convolutional neural networks and restricted boltzmann machines for semantic segmentation of object parts.

Peer-reviewed Conference Publications

- GIFT: Generalizable Interaction-aware Functional Tool Affordances without Labels, RSS 2021
 - D. Turpin, L. Wang, S. Tsogkas, S. Dickinson, A. Garg
- - T. Aumentado-Armstrong, A. Levinshtein, S. Tsogkas, K. Derpanis, A. Jepson
- \bullet Few-Shot Single-View 3D Reconstruction with Compositional Priors, ECCV~2020
 - M. Michalkiewicz, S. Parisot, **S. Tsogkas**, M. Baktashmotlagh, A. Eriksson, E. Belilovsky
- Appearance Shock Grammar for Fast Medial Axis Extraction from Real Images, CVPR 2020
 - COD. Camaro, M. Rezanejad, S. Tsogkas, K. Siddiqi, S. Dickinson
- Geometric Disentanglement for Generative Latent Shape Models, ICCV 2019
 T. Aumentado-Armstrong, S. Tsogkas, A. Jepson, S. Dickinson
- DeepFlux for Skeletons in the Wild, CVPR 2019
 Y. Wang, Y. Xu, S. Tsogkas, X. Bei, S. Dickinson, K. Siddiqi
- AMAT: Medial Axis Transform for Natural Images, ICCV 2017
 S. Tsogkas, S. Dickinson
- Prior-based Coregistration and Cosegmentation, MICCAI 2016
 M. Shakeri*, E. Ferrante*, S. Tsogkas, S. Lippe, S. Kadoury, I. Kokkinos, N. Paragios (* denotes equal contribution)
- Subcortical Brain Structure Segmentation Using FCNNs, ISBI 2016 (oral)
 S. Tsogkas*, M. Shakeri*, E. Ferrante, S. Lippe, S. Kadoury, N. Paragios, I. Kokkinos (* denotes equal contribution)
- Accurate Human-Limb Segmentation in RGB-D images for Intelligent Mobility Assistance Robots
 - ICCV 2015 3rd Workshop on Assistive Computer Vision and Robotics S. Chandra, S. Tsogkas, I. Kokkinos
- Deformable Part Models with CNN Features,
 ECCV 2014 Parts and Attributes workshop
 P.-A. Savalle, S. Tsogkas, G. Papandreou and I. Kokkinos
- Superpixel-grounded Deformable Part Models, CVPR 2014
 E. Trulls, S. Tsogkas, I. Kokkinos, A. Sanfeliu, F.Moreno
- Understanding Objects in Detail with Fine-grained Attributes, CVPR 2014
 A. Vedaldi, S. Mahendran, S. Tsogkas, S. Maji, B. Girshick, J. Kannala, E. Rahtu, I. Kokkinos, M. B. Blaschko, D. Weiss, B. Taskar, K. Simonyan, N. Saphra, S. Mohamed
- Learning-Based Symmetry Detection in Natural Images, ECCV 2012
 S. Tsogkas, I. Kokkinos

Journal publications

- Learning Compositional Shape Priors for Few-Shot 3D Reconstruction, (under submission to TPAMI)
 - M. Michalkiewicz, **S. Tsogkas**, S. Parisot, M. Baktashmotlagh, A. Eriksson, E. Belilovsky
- Disentangling Geometric Deformation Spaces in Generative Latent Shape Models, (under submission to IJCV)
 - T. Aumentado-Armstrong, S. Tsogkas, S. Dickinson, A. Jepson

DeepFlux for Skeleton Detection in the Wild, IJCV 2021
 Y. Xu, Y. Wang, S. Tsogkas, J. Wan, X. Bai, S. Dickinson, K. Siddiqi

Reports

- ICCV 2017 Challenge: Detecting Symmetry in the Wild (editorial),

 Detecting symmetry in the wild workshop, ICCV 2017

 Chris Funk*, Seungkyu Lee*, Martin R. Oswald*, Stavros Tsogkas*, Wei
 Shen, Andrea Cohen, Sven Dickinson, Yanxi Liu (* denotes equal contribution)
- Deep Learning for Semantic Part Segmentation with High-Level Guidance, $arXiv\ report$
 - S. Tsogkas, I. Kokkinos, G. Papandreou, A. Vedaldi

Teaching Experience

Teaching assistant (CentraleSupélec)

2011-2015

- Signal Processing (undegrad course).
- Computer Vision (undegrad course).
- Machine Learning for Computer Vision (MVA master course)

Invited lecturer (CentraleSupélec/ESSEC)

2016

MSc in Data Science and Business Analytics Seminar on deep learning theory and tools.

Professional Activities

Reviewer, IEEE TPAMI, IJCV, CVIU, IMAVIS, IEEE ICCV, IEEE CVPR, ECCV, ICVGIP, BMVC, Morgan & Claypool Synthesis lectures on Computer Vision

Co-organizer of the "Detecting Symmetry in the Wild" workshop,

in conjunction with ICCV 2017, Venice, Italy.

Treasurer, IEEE NTUA Student Branch2010-2011Chairman, IEEE NTUA Student Branch2011-2012Student member IEEE2012-2015

Programming Skills

MATLAB, Python, Lua, C++, Latex, Caffe, MatConvNet, Torch.

Distinctions

Outstanding reviewer award (ECCV 2016)

Citizenship

Greek

Languages

English (fluent), French (proficient), Greek (native).